Make room for new emotions.
Inside Out 2 is a animation, adventure, comedy film directed by Kelsey Mann.
Teenager Riley's mind headquarters is undergoing a sudden demolition to
make room for something entirely unexpected: new Emotions!
Joy, Sadness, Anger, Fear and Disgust, who’ve long been running a successful
operation by all accounts, aren’t sure how to feel when Anxiety shows up.
And it looks like she’s not alone.
Joy (voice), played by Amy Poehler.
Anxiety (voice), played by Maya Hawke.
Riley (voice), played by Kensington Tallman.
Disgust (voice), played by Liza Lapira.
Fear (voice), played by Tony Hale.
Anger (voice), played by Lewis Black.
Inside Out 2 is a 2024 American animated coming-of-age film produced
by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
The sequel to Inside Out (2015), it was directed by Kelsey Mann in his feature film directorial debut and was produced by Mark
Nielsen, from a screenplay written by Meg LeFauve and Dave Holstein, and a story conceived by Mann and LeFauve.
Amy Poehler, Phyllis Smith, Lewis Black, Diane Lane, and Kyle MacLachlan reprise their roles from the first film, with Maya Hawke, Kensington Tallman (replacing Kaitlyn Dias from the first film), Liza Lapira (replacing
Mindy Kaling from the first film), Tony Hale (replacing Bill Hader from the first film), Ayo Edebiri, Lilimar, Grace Lu, Sumayyah Nuriddin-Green, Adèle Exarchopoulos, and Paul Walter Hauser joining the cast.
The film follows Riley's emotions unexpectedly joined by new
emotions, eager to take control of her mind.
Development on Inside Out 2 began in early 2020, with Mann drawing
inspiration from personal childhood experiences.
The creative team initially explored a wider range of new emotions before narrowing the
focus for narrative clarity, with Anxiety emerging as a central addition.
Clinical psychologists, including Lisa Damour and Dacher Keltner, were consulted to ensure an accurate portrayal of
adolescent emotional development, while a group of teenagers provided feedback on character and story authenticity.
The film's premise shifted during development from a
talent show to Riley's involvement in hockey.
The production also marked the first Pixar feature
scored by a woman, Andrea Datzman.
Animation development emphasized spatial consistency through isometric mapping, and casting changes were driven
in part by compensation disputes, resulting in the recasting of the characters Fear and Disgust.
Inside Out 2 premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on
June 10, 2024, and was released in the United States on June 14.
The film received positive reviews from critics and was a massive box office success, grossing $1.699 billion worldwide, breaking multiple box-office records, becoming the
highest-grossing film by Pixar and the highest-grossing animated film of all time, though was later overtaken by Ne Zha 2 (2025) in just nine months after its initial release.
It also became the highest-grossing film of 2024 and the
eighth-highest-grossing film at the time of its release.
The film received nominations for Best Animated Feature at the Golden
Globes, Critics' Choice, BAFTAs and Academy Awards.
It additionally received a nomination for Cinematic and Box
Office Achievement at the Golden Globes.
The film explores themes of sadness, disgust,
sequel, computer animation, teenage girl.
The tone is lighthearted.